<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about on Stanislav Gobunov</title>
    <link>https://gobunov.com/tags/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about on Stanislav Gobunov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gobunov.com/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>Stanislav Gobunov ​	Moscow, Russia
​	stas@gobunov.com
​	gobunov.com
Position Head of Developers Head of Operations Teamlead Developer Expert Skills ​	Extensive experience in IT, including system programming, network programming, consulting, system administration, project management and leadership team. Broad-minded in IT. Knowledge and understanding of current trends.
​	Understanding the principles of design and implementation of large corporate systems, information security systems. Knowledge of the principles and ways to manage information systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/cv_ru/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/cv_ru/</guid>
      <description>Станислав Гобунов Москва, Россия
stas@gobunov.com
gobunov.com
Позиция Руководитель отдела разработчиков Руководитель отдела поддержки DevOps Разработчик/Программист Эксперт/Консультант Teamlead Навыки ​	Обширный опыт в ИТ, включая поддержку пользователей, системное администрирование, системное программирование, сетевое программирование, консалтинг, управление проектами и руководства командой. Широкий кругозор в ИТ. Знание и понимание современных тенденций.
​	Опыт в разработке и реализации средних и крупных программных и технических систем. Опыт руководства группой, отделом разработчиков, технических специалистов. Серьезный консалтинговый опыт. Опыт разработки корпоративных проектов по информационной безопасности и распределенным информационным системам.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>/</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/home/</guid>
      <description>I am certified computer professional, programmer and a DevOps specialist. Feel free to contact.
See about page for more information.
See posts page for recent posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am certified computer professional, programmer and a DevOps specialist.
Broad experience in IT, ranging from providing user support, system administration, systems programming, network programming to consulting, project and people management.
Wide experience in a analysis, design and programming in various medium to large scale environments. Team leadership experience. Significant consulting experience. Enterprise-wide projects on information security and information systems experience.
Understanding of enterprise-wide information systems principles and implementation practices. Understanding of information systems security principles and implementation methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Mac OSX port of FBReader Experimental build of 0.10.x branch
Experimental build of latest version 0.10.7 released. Compiled with Qt version 4.5, fribidi version 0.9.10, linebreak version 1.1.
Now you can access SVN repository of port source on GoogleCode and GitHub.
Port of latest version 0.8.17
Great news! Port of latest version 0.8.17 released. No installation package, no need of external libraries now. Standart Mac OS X application. PowerPC support added.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
