<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Stanislav Gobunov</title>
    <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Stanislav Gobunov</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gobunov.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links 24-05-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-240509/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-240509/</guid>
      <description>Dev Top 50 System Design Interview Questions for 2024 &amp;ndash; System design interviews have become a crucial component in evaluating a candidate&amp;rsquo;s capacity to solve real-world challenges, assess trade-offs, and design systems that can handle complex requirements.&#xA;Go size analyzer &amp;ndash; A simple tool to analyze the size of a Go compiled binary.&#xA;Ops bumblebee-status &amp;ndash; modular, theme-able status line generator for the i3 window manager.&#xA;Focus is on:&#xA;ease of use, sane defaults (no mandatory configuration file) easy creation of custom themes easy creation of custom modules Awesome DevOps Telegram &amp;ndash; A curated list of public Telegram channels and groups (chats) dedicated to DevOps, SRE, and Platform Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Предупреждаем вас не Г., не М. и не С.</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B4%D1%83%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B6%D0%B4%D0%B0%D0%B5%D0%BC-%D0%B2%D0%B0%D1%81-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D0%B3.-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D0%BC.-%D0%B8-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D1%81./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B4%D1%83%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B6%D0%B4%D0%B0%D0%B5%D0%BC-%D0%B2%D0%B0%D1%81-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D0%B3.-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D0%BC.-%D0%B8-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D1%81./</guid>
      <description>informaticslib.ru&#xA;В. Пекелис, 1970 E-Mail webmaster.innobi@gmail.com&#xA;20–29 minutes&#xA;Предупреждаем вас не Г., не М. и не С. Эту фразу для названия я взял из фельетона &amp;ldquo;Проклятая кибернетика&amp;rdquo; знаменитого американского фельетониста Арта Бухвальда. Что она значит, вы поймете, прочитав фельетон. Я привожу его полностью:&#xA;Счета нам сейчас рассылаются обычно в виде перфорированных карточек для электронных вычислительных машин. На карточках крупными буквами напечатано. НЕ ГНУТЬ, НЕ МЯТЬ, НЕ СКРУЧИВАТЬ! У меня есть приятель, который терпеть не может, чтобы ему указывали, что ему делать и чего не делать со счетами.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 24-01-07</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-240124/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-240124/</guid>
      <description>Dev Role of algorithms &amp;ndash; Algorithms are a useful skill not because you use it at work every day, but because they train you to be better at particular aspects of software engineering.&#xA;Database Fundamentals &amp;ndash; basically a short summary of Designing Data Intensive Applications and Database Internals, with a focus on the fundamental problems a database engineer thinks about in the shower.&#xA;Go 1.22: Interactive release notes &amp;ndash; A useful run down of the changes in the upcoming Go 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 23-07-06</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230706/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230706/</guid>
      <description>Dev Advanced Python Tips for Development &amp;ndash; explore 15 advanced Python tips that can help improve your development workflow and make your code more efficient.&#xA;Postgres: The Graph Database You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Know You Had &amp;ndash; PostgreSQL can be used for a wide range of sometimes surprising database needs. This post explains how to store graph data in Posgtres.&#xA;Ops Replace dockerfile with dagger &amp;ndash; Dockerfile is ubiquitous, but if you’d rather write container build scripts in other languages then Dagger allows that and lots more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 23-06-07</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230607/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230607/</guid>
      <description>Dev Why SQLite is so great for the edge &amp;ndash; SQLite has always seen use for interesting use cases, this post looks at why it’s particularly useful for edge applications, and describes a new open source fork aimed at building a contributor community.&#xA;10 Books to Improve Coding Skill in 2023.&#xA;Big O Notation: A Simple Explanation With Examples &amp;ndash; In this article, we’ll cover the basics of Big O notation, why it is used and how describe the time and space complexity of algorithms with an example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 23-05-05</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230505/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230505/</guid>
      <description>Dev ko &amp;ndash; a simple, fast container image builder for Go applications.&#xA;Codon &amp;ndash; Codon is a high-performance Python compiler that compiles Python code to native machine code without any runtime overhead.&#xA;6 Ways To Boost the Performance of Your Go Applications &amp;ndash; Optimizing your Go applications.&#xA;Go&amp;rsquo;s Error Handling Is a Form of Storytelling.&#xA;The Tao of Go &amp;ndash; What is the Tao of Go, and how can we work with it, like a surfer going with the waves instead of struggling against them?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 23-03-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230323/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230323/</guid>
      <description>Dev Build Server With Go Under 10 minutes.&#xA;free-for.dev &amp;ndash; a list of software (SaaS, PaaS, IaaS, etc.) and other offerings that have free tiers for developers.&#xA;A Practical Guide to Concurrency in Golang — Key Terms and Examples &amp;ndash; concurrency in Golang with an example of sentiment data processing using goroutines, channels, waitgroups, and many more terms.&#xA;Software and Architectural Design Patterns &amp;ndash; A curated list of software and architecture related design patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 23-02-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230223/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230223/</guid>
      <description>Dev Go Errors Cheat Sheet 2022 &amp;ndash; discussion about the different types of errors in Go, including Sentinel Errors and Error Types, and how to compare errors using the errors.Is and errors.As functions.&#xA;Rust vs Go in 2023 &amp;ndash; Which is better, Rust or Go? Go or Rust? Which language should you choose for your next project in 2023, and why?&#xA;Building a URL Shortener Using Go and Sqlite &amp;ndash; Ever wondered how a URL shortener works?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 23-01-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-230123/</guid>
      <description>Dev A Guide to the Most Popular Types of APIs: REST, SOAP, GraphQL, and gRPC.&#xA;REST API vs GraphQL.&#xA;Monoliths vs Microservices vs Serverless &amp;ndash; the tradeoffs that each option presents.&#xA;Textual &amp;ndash; a Python framework for creating interactive applications that run in your terminal.&#xA;OOP in Go &amp;ndash; How to use Object Oriented Programming in Go.&#xA;Go: Arrays and Slices, a deep dive &amp;ndash; In this article we&amp;rsquo;re going to discuss all there is to know about arrays and slices in Go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 22-11-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-221122/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-221122/</guid>
      <description>Dev Restful API with Golang practical approach &amp;ndash; tutorial for creating a Restful API with a practical approach of clean architecture and native Golang without any frameworks.&#xA;How I’m a Productive Programmer With a Memory of a Fruit Fly &amp;ndash; Programming got vastly more varied compared to when I started dabbling in AmigaBASIC in the mid-1990s. Back then you could buy one very big book about the computer you’re programming and were 99% there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 22-09-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220922/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220922/</guid>
      <description>Dev Aging programmer &amp;ndash; Back in college, they told me that I would start my career writing code, but eventually, I would move to a position where I would ask others to code my designs. To celebrate that this turned out to be completely false, here are some assorted reflections as a 40-year-old programmer that looks back.&#xA;How we reduced our annual server costs by 80% &amp;ndash; Zsot Varga shares how Prerender saved $800k by removing their reliance on AWS and building in-house infrastructure to handle traffic and cached data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 27-07-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220727/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220727/</guid>
      <description>Dev Learn Makefiles With the tastiest examples &amp;ndash; Makefiles are everywhere in DevOps, so it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth learning about make. This resource starts from quite a one-sided introduction to make (as a build tool for C++ projects), but the rest is full of useful information. Also, looking at make from the angle of a build (i.e., file manipulation) tool could explain many of its quirks.&#xA;How We Halved Go Monorepo CI Build Time &amp;ndash; A detailed post on drastically reducing the build time of a large, complex Go project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 22-06-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220622/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220622/</guid>
      <description>Dev ugit &amp;ndash; CLI undo git commands.&#xA;forgit &amp;ndash; tool is to help you use git more efficiently. It&amp;rsquo;s lightweight and easy to use.&#xA;How to bootstrap a quality Go backend &amp;ndash; This post will help you choose an HTTP framework, design a scalable folder structure, establish good practices for a test suite, and more.&#xA;Syncing text files between browser and disk using Yjs and the File System Access API &amp;ndash; In this post, we look at the newly introduced File System Access API, which lets the browser read and write files on a computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 22-05-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220522/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220522/</guid>
      <description>Dev Modern Microprocessors - A 90-Minute Guide! &amp;ndash; Okay, so you&amp;rsquo;re a CS graduate and you did a hardware course as part of your degree, but perhaps that was a few years ago now and you haven&amp;rsquo;t really kept up with the details of processor designs since then.&#xA;Learn Go: The complete course &amp;ndash; Welcome to the course, and thanks for learning Go.&#xA;The Ultimate Guide To Software Engineering &amp;ndash; This article will discuss the skills needed to become an excellent software engineer and how you can learn them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 22-03-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220322/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220322/</guid>
      <description>Dev Could Rust be the future of JavaScript infrastructure? &amp;ndash; The Future of JavaScript Tooling.&#xA;Some mistakes Rust doesn’t catch &amp;ndash; When you look at all the combinations of all possible instructions in a programming language, only a tiny fraction are useful programs. Even fewer actually achieve the task you’ve set out to do. So rather than looking at what a programming language can do, perhaps a better way is to look at what it won’t let you do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 22-02-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220222/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-220222/</guid>
      <description>Dev Awesome cheatsheets for popular programming languages, frameworks and development tools. They include everything you should know in one single file.&#xA;GPS &amp;ndash; Global Positioning System is, without a doubt, one of the most useful inventions of the late 20th century. It made it significantly easier for ships, airplanes, cars, and hikers to figure out where they are with high degree of accuracy.&#xA;How we saved 70K cores across 30 mission-critical services &amp;ndash; As part of Uber engineering’s wide efforts to reach profitability, recently our team was focused on reducing cost of compute capacity by improving efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-12-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-211222/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-211222/</guid>
      <description>Dev Zinc &amp;ndash; Zinc is a search engine that does full text indexing. It is a lightweight alternative to Elasticsearch and runs in less than 100 MB of RAM. It uses bluge as the underlying indexing library. Ops Computer networking basics every developer should know &amp;ndash; As a software engineer, I need to deal with networking every now and then - be it configuring a SOHO network, setting up container networking, or troubleshooting connectivity between servers in a data center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-11-11</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-211111/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-211111/</guid>
      <description>Dev Scripting languages of the future &amp;ndash; Some thoughts about the future of scripting languages, interesting given this is where much of the code operations teams write resides.&#xA;Learn Golang by building a fintech banking app.&#xA;Awesome Learning Resources 1.&#xA;Awesome Learning Resources 2.&#xA;Learn to code.&#xA;ProjectLearn: Project Based Learning.&#xA;Structured logging in Python &amp;ndash; A how to on setting up structured logging for Python applications.&#xA;Create a Restful API with Golang from scratch &amp;ndash; Learn how to structure an API with Golang, dockerize it, setup VSCode debugger and improve your knowledge of the language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-10-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-211021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-211021/</guid>
      <description>Dev 20 things I’ve learned in my 20 years as a software engineer &amp;ndash; You’re about to read a blog post with a lot of advice. Learning from those who came before us is instrumental to success, but we often forget an important caveat. Almost all advice is contextual, yet it is rarely delivered with any context. Ops Tools to explore BGP &amp;ndash; Yesterday there was a big Facebook outage caused by BGP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-09-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210921/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210921/</guid>
      <description>Dev B-Trees: More than I thought I&amp;rsquo;d want to know &amp;ndash; Recently, I’ve been reading through the excellent Database Internals (Alex Petrov, 2019). The first half of the book is dedicated to the implementation of database storage engines – the subsystem(s) of a DBMS that handles long-term persistence of data. A surprising amount of this section discusses the implementation and optimization of various B-Tree data structures.&#xA;How writing can advance your career as a developer &amp;ndash; In their ﬁrst few years on the job, engineers spend roughly 30% of their workday writing, while engineers in middle management write for 50% to 70% of their day; those in senior management reportedly spend over 70% and as much as 95% of their day writing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-08-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210821/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210821/</guid>
      <description>Dev Folk wisdom on visual programming &amp;ndash; Brought to you by Hacker News readers.&#xA;Programming language memory models &amp;ndash; “Programming language memory models answer the question of what behaviors parallel programs can rely on to share memory between their threads.” Here’s a look at formalizing programming language memory models from Go language team lead Russ Cox.&#xA;Zip: How not to design a file format &amp;ndash; The Zip file format is now 32 years old.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-07-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210721/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210721/</guid>
      <description>Dev Dates and times in Go &amp;ndash; Keeping track of time in code can be a headache. This tutorial takes a look at managing time in Go.&#xA;New protocol types in Python 3.8 &amp;ndash; The new protocol class in Python 3.8 enables structural typing and other idiomatic patterns in Python. This article explains the protocols and their features.&#xA;7 GitHub projects to make you a better Go Developer &amp;ndash; 7 amazing GitHub projects that will help you become a better Go developer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-06-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210621/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210621/</guid>
      <description>Dev Best practices for code review &amp;ndash; There’s no such thing as perfect code—that’s why we need code review. But it doesn’t have to be painful.&#xA;Text editing hates you too &amp;ndash; Back in 2017, I was building a rich text editor in the browser. Unsatisfied with existing libraries that used ContentEditable, I thought to myself &amp;ldquo;hey, I&amp;rsquo;ll just reimplement text selection myself! How difficult could it possibly be?&amp;rdquo; I was young.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-05-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210521/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210521/</guid>
      <description>Dev The beauty of programming &amp;ndash; I don’t know how to really explain my fascination with programming, but I’ll try. To somebody who does it, it’s the most interesting thing in the world. It’s a game much more involved than chess, a game where you can make up your own rules and where the end result is whatever you can make of it. And yet, to the outside, it looks like the most boring thing on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-04-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210421/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210421/</guid>
      <description>Dev Rust and Go: Better together &amp;ndash; If you’re thinking in terms of Rust or Go, you may be missing a pairing of the two that has worked well for companies like Dropbox, Fastly, and Cloudflare. Here’s a look at the pros and cons of Rust and Go, how they complement each other, and when each language is more appropriate. [#golang,#rust]&#xA;Safe Systems Programming in Rust &amp;ndash; Rust overcomes the trade-off between the safety of higher-level languages and the control over resource management provided by lower-level systems programming languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-03-30</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210330/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210330/</guid>
      <description>Dev Go may be simple. But it’s not easy. &amp;ndash; The syntax is simple. Most of the semantics are simple. But getting something done can sometimes be deceptively hard. Martin Tournoij takes a look at the not-so-easy parts of Go (and what you can do about them). [#golang]&#xA;3 mindsets to avoid as a senior software developer &amp;ndash; I’m a self-taught programmer, and I need no one. I’m better than younger programmers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-03-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210301/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210301/</guid>
      <description>Dev Why is it so hard to see code from 5 minutes ago? &amp;ndash; A study found that Java developers backtracked every 6 minutes, meaning they reverted their code to a previous state (e.g., by clicking undo or pressing Ctrl-Z). These undo actions come in bursts and are often followed by successive redo actions. In fact, one participant in a different study used undo/redo 40 times in 5 minutes! When asked why they did this, they revealed they were trying to view some intermediate state of the code in the middle of a change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-02-10</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210210/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210210/</guid>
      <description>Dev Directory of Pragmatic Programmer Books on Medium &amp;ndash; Below is content you know and love from the Pragmatic Bookshelf, optimized for learning and enjoyment on the Medium platform.&#xA;Unsafe Rust (and when to use it) &amp;ndash; Rust contributor Andre Bogus explains unsafe Rust, dissects some of the myths that have built up around it, and provides advice on when to use it (and when not to).&#xA;Python tricks I can’t live without &amp;ndash; Sebastian Opałczyński offers up the code fragments he finds himself using again and again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-02-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210201/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210201/</guid>
      <description>Dev 10 Advanced Projects to Build in 2021 &amp;ndash; curated a list of 10 advanced projects to complete in 2021. Most of these are systems programming projects, but there are a few other AI and networking projects in the list.&#xA;Functional Programming as Algebra &amp;ndash; Let’s return to everyone’s “favorite” subject. 🙄&#xA;How to become a more efficient Python programmer &amp;ndash; If you want to write the most readable and computationally efficient code, this tutorial shows you the best ways to create lists and accomplish other tasks in Python.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-01-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210121/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210121/</guid>
      <description>Dev The Five Books that Changed my Life as a Software Engineer &amp;ndash; The five books that have had the biggest impact on one dev community.&#xA;RESTful API Design: Best Practices &amp;ndash; Some community-recommended best practices to follow while designing and developing RESTful APIs.&#xA;State machines are wonderful tools &amp;ndash; State machines are perhaps one of those concepts you heard about in college but never put into practice. Maybe you use them regularly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-01-10</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210110/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210110/</guid>
      <description>Dev 65 Things I wish I knew when I started to Code &amp;ndash; If you are a new, aspiring developer, these 65 things will prepare you for the long journey ahead. Use them as a shortcut in your own learning path.&#xA;Server Rendering in JavaScript: Why SSR? &amp;ndash; Server-Side Rendering is all the talk with the JavaScript framework world right now. There are obvious examples like Vercels Next.js which made the news with getting $40M in new funding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 21-01-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-210101/</guid>
      <description>Dev Command Line Interface Guidelines &amp;ndash; An open-source guide to help you write better command-line programs, taking traditional UNIX principles and updating them for the modern day. [#cli]&#xA;My Engineering Axioms &amp;ndash; things that, over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to think of as generally true and useful to have in mind when writing code, building things, and working with others.&#xA;Rust Reviewed: Is the hype justified? &amp;ndash; a reflection on golden moments and pain points with Rust in the past year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-12-20</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-201220/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-201220/</guid>
      <description>Dev Codepath &amp;ndash; fundamental CodePath Computer Science guides on data structures, algorithms and technical interviewing!&#xA;5 Podcasts Every Dev Must Listen To &amp;ndash; A list of technical podcasts that are meant to inspire and help educate developers.&#xA;5 Ways Software Developers Can Improve Their Writing Beyond Blogging &amp;ndash; business writing.&#xA;Writing a Book with Pandoc, Make, and Vim &amp;ndash; book-writing setup using Pandoc, vim, makefile, plus Preview app on macOS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-12-12</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-201212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-201212/</guid>
      <description>Dev An ex-Googler&amp;rsquo;s guide to dev tools &amp;ndash; Many years ago, I did a brief stint at Google. A lot has changed since then, but even that brief exposure to Google&amp;rsquo;s internal developer tools left a lasting impression on me. In many ways, the dev tools inside Google are the most advanced in the world.&#xA;Exotic Programming Ideas: Effect Systems &amp;ndash; Continuing on in our series on exotic programming ideas, we’re going to explore the topic of effects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-11-11</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-201111/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-201111/</guid>
      <description>Dev Rust vs Go &amp;ndash; Both Go, and more recently Rust, are increasingly popular for infrastructure tooling. This post has a nice comparison of the languages, looking at the main similarities and differences. [#go]&#xA;Hands-free coding &amp;ndash; Here’s how Josh Comeau develops software using dictation and eye tracking. [#dictation]&#xA;Architecture Playbook &amp;ndash; Smart people have been thinking on how to create IT architectures as long as there has been computers. Ideas come and go, however creating a good architectures can still be complex and time consuming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-08-08</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200808/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200808/</guid>
      <description>Dev StackOverflow’s 2020 developer survey. [#survey]&#xA;The least liked programming languages &amp;ndash; Why are they so dreaded? And are they being evaluated fairly? [#languages]&#xA;Go versus Rust: Writing a CLI tool &amp;ndash; Want to test your skills? Try implementing a CLI tool in more than one language. Paulo Henrique Cuchi used Rust (source) and Go (source) and describes his process in this tutorial. [#cli]&#xA;How to package Python apps with BeeWare Briefcase &amp;ndash; Unlike other languages like Rust or Go, Python doesn’t have a consistent internal mechanism for generating a stand-alone binary from an application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-07-31</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200731/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200731/</guid>
      <description>Dev 5 Python features you (probably) didn’t know Here’s a look at a few less common, but useful, features.&#xA;Go is boring (and that’s fantastic):&#xA;“If you look at the past 10 years in programming languages, you’ll see lots of changes. C++, Java, Python, and JavaScript have gained new features, and new languages like Rust and Swift have changed rapidly since their introduction. This is all pretty exciting but it also feels like sometimes you can never catch up with all the ideas in all these languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-05-30</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200530/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200530/</guid>
      <description>Dev These free tools for developers are - an editorialized roundup of free alternatives to the tools developers use to do their work and create their passion project.&#xA;Python Developers Survey results &amp;ndash; Over 24,000 Python developers from more than 150 different countries took the survey to provide a snapshot of Python use today.&#xA;Go as the language of cloud infrastructure &amp;ndash; In this interview, Rob Pike (coauthor of the Go programming language) discusses static typing, concurrency, and the future of Go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-05-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200501/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200501/</guid>
      <description>Dev Dockerize your Development Environment &amp;ndash; how to use Visual Studio Code and Docker to mimic your production settings and create consistency across the development environments.&#xA;I Built a Site for the Best Coding Fonts &amp;ndash; a project that shows off some of the most-love coding fonts with interactive previewing.&#xA;Wow! COBOL Programming Course &amp;ndash; This project is a set of training materials and labs for a &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; level course on COBOL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-04-12</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200412/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200412/</guid>
      <description>Dev 30 simple tricks to level up your Python coding &amp;ndash; You can write nonidiomatic (non-Pythonic) Python programs. It’s less readable, but odds are good it’ll work. Still, if you want to avoid annoying future coders who see (and judge, possibly harshly) your work, you might want to consider Yong Cui’s 30 tips for idiomatic Python development.&#xA;How to use pandas read_html to scrape data from HTML tables &amp;ndash; Here’s a step-by-step tutorial on how to use the pandas read_html method for scraping data from HTML.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-03-28</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200320/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200320/</guid>
      <description>Dev Learn Rust in 30 minutes or less &amp;ndash; Amos Wenger blazes through as many Rust snippets as you can read in half an hour. By the time you’re through, “you should be able to read most of the Rust code you find online.”&#xA;Advanced Go concurrency &amp;ndash; For now, employers may love Go more than engineers do (at least, according to Hired’s 2020 State of Software Engineers report) but that’s likely to change if demand remains high.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-02-29</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200229/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200229/</guid>
      <description>Dev The 25 most recommended programming books of all-time &amp;ndash; a short list of book recommendations, compiled from seventy articles.&#xA;Learn To Code By Playing These Games &amp;ndash; six gamification platforms for learning popular programming languages.&#xA;What is O(log n)? Learn Big O Logarithmic Time Complexity &amp;ndash; the fundamentals of Big O logarithmic time complexity with examples in JavaScript.&#xA;The RedMonk Programming Language Rankings &amp;ndash; January 2020.&#xA;Ops Ansible vs Puppet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-02-20</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200220/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200220/</guid>
      <description>Dev Daemonize and scale your Python apps &amp;ndash; This two-part series helps you make sense of distributed processing with Python daemons. In part one, you’ll learn how to create daemon processes using Unix-specific packages. Then, in part two, you’ll learn how to do the same using the equivalent Windows services.&#xA;The best Python IDEs and packages around - here’s a roundup of the top 10 Python IDEs and code editors. And here are the 22 most-used Python packages in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-02-02</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200202/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200202/</guid>
      <description>Dev Monoliths are the future &amp;ndash; At least that&amp;rsquo;s Kelsey Hightower&amp;rsquo;s “unpopular opinion,” developed while going “from microservices to monoliths and back again. Both directions.” Read why in this excerpt from his appearance on the Go Time podcast or just listen to the whole episode.&#xA;Everyone undervalues the gc compiler &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Even the Go community itself doesn’t fully appreciate it.&amp;rdquo; But they should. Chris Wellons explains why gc will blow you away if you give it a chance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where are we headed in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200120/</guid>
      <description>As we enter a new decade, we asked programming experts, including several of our own O’Reilly authors and instructors, for their thoughts on what’s in store for some established players and fast-growing languages.&#xA;Python The biggest news this year in Python is that creator and “benevolent dictator for life” Guido van Rossum retired, leaving Python in the hands of the Python Steering Council. So far, it’s been a painless shift in power, which as Eric Matthes, author of Python Crash Course, argues, should come as no surprise, since “Guido has carried himself, and his role in the community, with such poise for so long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 20-01-10</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200110/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-200110/</guid>
      <description>Dev It finally happened! ;) Well designed and carefully colored Borland/Turbo C++ flavor ui system combined with vim&amp;rsquo;s productivity.&#xA;Must-know topic for all programmers: How different are Python and C++? &amp;ndash; Well, maybe not all programmers, but if you’d like to know, Farhad Malik has you covered.&#xA;Here’s Javin Paul’s path to becoming a Java expert.&#xA;Ops The Complete DevOps Developer RoadMap &amp;ndash; Your Guide to become DevOps Engineer. tail -f /dev/misc 42 essential open source software projects that drive science &amp;ndash; The Chan Zuckerberg Initiative is awarding 42 open source projects with grants under its Essential Open Source Software for Science program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-12-31</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191231/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191231/</guid>
      <description>Dev Programming Languages To Learn In 2020 To Boost Your Career As A Software Developer &amp;ndash; our language to learn for those inspired by polygot programming.&#xA;How to Code in Go &amp;ndash; a series of tutorials to help you learn how to code in Go.&#xA;Go reading list &amp;ndash; You&amp;rsquo;ll probably have some downtime this holiday season. Why not use it to bone up on Go with this extensive list of &amp;ldquo;Important Reading&amp;rdquo; resources from Bill Kennedy?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-12-12</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191212/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191212/</guid>
      <description>Dev My first impressions of Rust &amp;ndash; an experienced programmer shares their likes and dislikes towards Rust.&#xA;27 Programming Youtube channels you should know &amp;ndash; a master list for those who like learnings through videos.&#xA;Security assessment techniques for Go projects &amp;ndash; From static analysis to fuzzing to using the Go compiler&amp;rsquo;s built-in features and beyond.&#xA;Staying responsive when CPU bound&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Recently [Ellation&amp;rsquo;s] team started working on a new microservice tasked with user logins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-11-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191109/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191109/</guid>
      <description>Dev The 7 programming languages employers actually want &amp;ndash; Sure, they&amp;rsquo;re the same usual suspects, but this brief article adds a little more context, including why .NET—a framework, not a language—may have made the list and why the list is more evidence of Python coming into its own.&#xA;How to gracefully shut down a program that uses Go coroutines &amp;ndash; You know, the ones &amp;ldquo;performing tasks that must be completed before allowing the program to shut down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-10-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191019/</guid>
      <description>Dev Rust for a home run &amp;ndash; This MLB playoff season why not dive deep into the data with Rust? Eli Ben-Porat shows you how to build a basic app that turns MLB Gameday XML files, which contain pitch-by-pitch data for every pitch thrown in affiliated baseball since 2008, into usable links&#xA;How to use plug-ins in Rust Writing helper scripts in bash? Use Go instead &amp;ndash; The benefits are many, as Krzysztof Kowalczyk explains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-10-10</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-191010/</guid>
      <description>Dev A road map to data science mastery &amp;ndash; Here&amp;rsquo;s an oldie but a goodie. Rebecca Vickery&amp;rsquo;s series from 2018 outlines a complete program for learning data science from scratch—all based on her own journey: Programming Skills, A Complete Roadmap for Learning Data Science — Part 1 Data Analysis, A Complete Roadmap for Learning Data Science — Part 2 Maths and Statistics, A Complete Roadmap for Learning Data Science — Part 3 Processing 40 TB of code from 10 million projects with a dedicated server and Go for $100 &amp;ndash; Well, not actually 10 million—it was only about 9,985,000.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-09-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190919/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190919/</guid>
      <description>Dev Mimic is a tool for authoring configuration in Go. It uses a provider model to help generate specific config files and offer a typed interface so you can use it for, for instance, generating HCL for Terraform and YAML for Kubernetes at the same time. Heap Maps 101 by Samantha Bretous &amp;ndash; tutorial on heap maps, also known as a heap, is a set of values stored in a specific order that allows efficient access or modification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-09-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190901/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190901/</guid>
      <description>Dev SEO Cheat Sheet for Devs &amp;ndash; a useful checklist for site launches or migrations. Why all the object-oriented programming hate &amp;ndash; Like most programming arguments, there&amp;rsquo;s no clear answer to whether object-oriented programming or functional programming is the better approach (although we bet you have an opinion). David Cassel wades into the debate, focusing on Ilya Suzdalnitski&amp;rsquo;s recent missive dubbing OOP a &amp;ldquo;trillion-dollar disaster,&amp;rdquo; to detail some of the pros and cons of OOP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-08-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190819/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190819/</guid>
      <description>Dev Tutorial guide about making a REST API. Acquire Git superpowers with these 6 tips &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Git [is] a must-have skill for developers. Yet many developers only know the basics—or worse, they cargo code the Git commands they use on a daily basis without really understanding what they are doing.&amp;rdquo; Get more productive with your Git. James Turnbull shows you how. It&amp;rsquo;s a trap! &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;ve written any amount of bash code, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely come across the trap command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-07-29</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190727/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190727/</guid>
      <description>Dev Why Codewars is the best way to learn a new programming language &amp;ndash; a fun way to learn a new language, if you already know the basics. 4 Ways You Can “Level Up” As A Developer &amp;ndash; from building a substantial project to learning more design patterns and principles. How to structure a multifile C program &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Grab your favorite beverage, editor, and compiler, crank up some tunes, and start structuring a C program composed of multiple files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-07-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190719/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190719/</guid>
      <description>Dev Python versus Go versus Rust: A subjective, primarily developer-ergonomics-based comparison &amp;ndash; Python developer Nicolas Hahn shares his experiences writing a program in the three languages. He found Python lean, Go less fun, and Rust more complex—but ultimately concludes, &amp;ldquo;In the end, this comparison is a bit silly, because though the use cases of these languages overlap, they occupy very different niches.&amp;rdquo; Python vs Node.Js: Which Programming Language to Choose? &amp;ndash; Every project has its specifications and demands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-06-29</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190629/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190629/</guid>
      <description>Dev Major (Kubernetes) fails &amp;ndash; Sometimes, stories about what went wrong can be just as inspiring as those about what went right. Forget monoliths versus microservices &amp;ndash; Cognitive load should be your organization&amp;rsquo;s guiding principle instead. 5 principles for cloud native architecture &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;The good news is that cloud is made of the same fabric of servers, disks, and networks that make up traditional infrastructure,&amp;rdquo; explains Tom Grey, head of cloud solutions architecture for EMEA at Google Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-06-16</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190616/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190616/</guid>
      <description>Dev How to start a software project with a quality mindset &amp;ndash; Building quality software is not an easy task and requires a lot of practice and experience. Top 5 Soft Skills for Software Engineer &amp;ndash; Soft skills are as critical as technical skills for a software engineer. No one works in isolation. Each person has to deal with teammates, colleagues, managers, etc. Therefore team interpersonal skills are essential too. Soft skills include things like good communication, honesty, teamwork, integrity, organization, empathy, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-06-07</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190607/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190607/</guid>
      <description>Dev Whose language is Go anyway? &amp;ndash; Here are two takes. In a post last week, Chris Siebenmann argued that “Go is Google’s language, not ours” (while also pointing out that he’s “basically okay with how the language has been evolving and how the Go core team has managed it”). Understanding Real-World Concurrency Bugs in Go &amp;ndash; As part of his Morning Paper series, Adrian Colyer examines “Understanding Real-World Concurrency Bugs in Go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-05-25</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190525/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190525/</guid>
      <description>Dev How to use React to create a cross-browser extension in 5 minutes &amp;ndash; Hu Chen built a Chrome extension that replaces new tab screen with GitHub trending projects using create-react-app. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it in five minutes. Entity Relationship Diagrams explained by Sonic the Hedgehog &amp;ndash; An Entity-Relationship Diagram (ERD) is a way to visualise relationships between tables and the common keys between them. On first glance, they may look like a spaghetti mess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-05-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190519/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190519/</guid>
      <description>Dev f-string debugging in Python 3.8 &amp;ndash; print style debugging is a form of debugging where print statements are inserted to print values of expressions or variables that we need to track. loggers are common if we want to use the log statements in production. But there are many times where quick print statements will do the trick in debugging and understanding the control flow. Weird Programming Languages &amp;ndash; More than a thousand programming languages have been invented and only about one hundred of them are commonly used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-05-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190513/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190513/</guid>
      <description>Dev 5 Best Programming Books for Beginners and Experts in 2019. Hacking the government: How the US Digital Services Agency uses Python &amp;ndash; On the latest episode of Podcast.init, host Tobias Macey talks with David Holmes, director of engineering for the USDS, about how the agency uses Python “to provide the greatest good to the largest number of people.” Listen in to find out how the USDS works, discover some of its most interesting—and most challenging—projects, and learn how you can get involved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-05-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190509/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 21:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190509/</guid>
      <description>Dev Python Chat Tutorial with Django and React &amp;ndash; Build chat with Python, Django, React and Stream Chat. 20 of Google&amp;rsquo;s Hardest Interview Questions for Software Engineers &amp;ndash; Google is notorious for asking hard interview questions. Many Software Engineers find their coding challenges extremely difficult, taking many months to prepare their skills. Programmers stay up all night solving problems on whiteboards, training to get the chance to work at Google. Writing production code that scales to billions of users can be difficult, so they look for the brightest of minds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-05-05</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190505/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190505/</guid>
      <description>Dev Learn by Contributing &amp;ndash; Contributing to open source projects helps you to improve your professional skills and discover new opportunities. Design for Non-Designers (Part 1) &amp;ndash; Even if you’re not a designer, you’ll need to do something visual, whether it’s making a landing page for your project, designing a form, creating your personal website, or making slides. Planning a Web Application &amp;ndash; Planning a non-trivial web application that performs some sort of functionality is something you may have done in the past or are in the midst of doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-04-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190421/</guid>
      <description>Dev [One secret to becoming a great software engineer: read code](https:// hackernoon.com/one-secret-to-becoming-a-great-software-engineer-read-code-467e31f243b0) &amp;ndash; become a better programmer by building a routine and habit for reading code. [Why software projects take longer than you think](https://erikbern.com/2019/ 04/15/why-software-projects-take-longer-than-you-think-a-statistical-model.html) &amp;ndash; Poor estimation of how long a software project will take “is really just a statistical artifact. Let’s say you estimate a project to take 1 week. Let’s say there are three equally likely outcomes: either it takes 1/2 week, or 1 week, or 2 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-04-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190413/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190413/</guid>
      <description>Dev Major Programming Trends to Prepare for in 2019 &amp;ndash; The new year is always a great time for reflection on the past year, but also a time to look forward to the next year and to imagine what’s to come.&#xA;Python v/s PHP: Which Programming Language to Choose in 2019? &amp;ndash; In today’s disruptive tech world, Python and PHP are the two most-popular server-side languages in use. In many aspects, Python and PHP closely compete with each other because of its almost identical features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-03-30</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190330/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190330/</guid>
      <description>Dev Major Programming Trends to Prepare for in 2019 &amp;ndash; Some of the major programming trends to prepare for to help you stay at the top of your game in 2019 — as well as a look back at the key programming themes of 2018.&#xA;3 Programming Languages to Learn in 2019 &amp;ndash; If you are new to the coding world, I recommend these languages.&#xA;Programming in Rust: the good, the bad, the ugly &amp;ndash; This post is about my experience learning Rust by solving every CtCI problem live on Twitch, an unfinished project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-03-16</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190316/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190316/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Git hacks you should know about](https://dev.to/teamxenox/ git-hacks-you-should-know-about-16pk) &amp;ndash; these could save you one day. [Top 10 books for getting started with automation testing](https:// www.lambdatest.com/blog/top-10-books-for-getting-started-with-automation-testing/) &amp;ndash; Automation testers, how are you doing with that 2019 reading list? Deeksha Agarwal has some titles you might want to add. [When &amp;ldquo;Zoë&amp;rdquo; !== &amp;ldquo;Zoë&amp;rdquo;; Or, why you need to normalize Unicode strings](https:// withblue.ink/2019/03/11/why-you-need-to-normalize-unicode-strings.html) &amp;ndash; “Never heard of Unicode normalization? You’re not alone. But it will save you a lot of trouble.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-03-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190309/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190309/</guid>
      <description>Dev Python: Understanding virtual environments &amp;ndash; Have you ever had a program crash when you tried to run it on a different machine? Has installing Python packages lead to incompatibility issues? If you’re new to Python, or never used virtual environments, this tutorial will walk you through the steps to properly set these up for each new project, and hopefully save you a headache along the way. How to distribute Python applications with PyInstaller &amp;ndash; “Wouldn’t it be great if your users could run your application without installing anything?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-03-03</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190303/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190303/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Understanding service workers and caching strategies](https://blog.bitsrc.io/ understanding-service-workers-and-caching-strategies-a6c1e1cbde03) &amp;ndash; Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide to service workers—and how to select a caching strategy. [If you want users to sign in, do this](http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/ dont-get-clever-with-login-forms) &amp;ndash; Don&amp;rsquo;t get clever with login forms. Make them simple, predictable, and linkable. And make sure they play nicely with password managers. [Lessons from 6 software rewrite stories stories](https://medium.com/ @herbcaudill/lessons-from-6-software-rewrite-stories-635e4c8f7c22) &amp;ndash; “Should you rewrite your application from scratch, or is that ‘the single worst strategic mistake that any software company can make’?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-02-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190223/</guid>
      <description>Dev [The Testing Introduction I Wish I Had](https://dev.to/maxwell_dev/ the-testing-introduction-i-wish-i-had-2dn) &amp;ndash; great overview of different types of tests, why testing matters, and general rules of thumb. [The Books That Made All The Difference To Me As A Developer](https://dev.to/ antjanus/the-books-that-made-all-the-difference-to-me-as-a-developer-1ijn) &amp;ndash; recommended reading for anyone looking to become a better developer. Hashnode CLI &amp;ndash; popular programming posts in your terminal. Hashnode is a free, friendly, and inclusive programming community! This is for terminal lovers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-02-16</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190216/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190216/</guid>
      <description>Dev [The future of computing is analog](https://medium.com/s/story/ the-future-of-computing-is-analog-e758471fbfe1) &amp;ndash; In this excerpt from his chapter “The Third Law,” George Dyson, a historian of science and technology, argues: We worry too much about machine intelligence and not enough about self-reproduction, communication, and control. The next revolution in computing will be signaled by the rise of analog systems over which digital programming no longer has control. Nature’s response to those who believe they can build machines to control everything will be to allow them to build a machine that controls them instead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-02-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190213/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190213/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Introductory Go Programming Tutorial](https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/ introductory-go-programming-tutorial) &amp;ndash; How to get started with this useful new programming language. [Grady Booch on the Future of AI](https://www.infoq.com/news/2019/02/ Grady-Booch-Future-AI) &amp;ndash; According to [Grady Booch](https://en.wikipedia.org/ wiki/Grady_Booch), most current AI systems are about pattern matching of signals at the edge and inductive reasoning, not true Artificial Intelligence. During his second day keynote at the 2018 QCon San Francisco, &amp;ldquo;Building the Enchanted Land&amp;rdquo;, he explained his view that AI today is a &amp;ldquo;system engineering problem with AI components.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-02-03</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190203/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190203/</guid>
      <description>Dev [HTTPS In Development: A Practical Guide](https://dev.to/kmaschta/ https-in-development-a-practical-guide-175m) &amp;ndash; Why and how to setup HTTPS certificates, with or without reverse proxy, in a your development environment. Dead Simple Python: Classes &amp;ndash; Classes and objects: the bread-and-butter of many a developer. Object-oriented programming is one of the mainstays of modern programming, so it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise that Python is capable of it. [Developer pet peeve: Not having clear role requirements](https:// research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-01-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190119/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190119/</guid>
      <description>Dev What’s new in SQLite? &amp;ndash; “SQLite is an undervalued database—some people even believe it is a toy database that is not suitable for production use. In fact, SQLite is a very solid database that can handle terabytes of data.” In this informative article, Markus Winand explores the new features that were added to SQLite in 2018. [How to make your Python workers scale dynamically](https://dzone.com/articles/ how-to-make-your-python-workers-scale-dynamically) &amp;ndash; At DZone, Maciej Gryka explains how QA platform company Rainforest scaled its application while supporting data science tools like scikit-learn and NumPy, sharing a flexible way to ship Python code for long-ish living workers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-01-11</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190111/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190111/</guid>
      <description>Dev Developer Roadmap in 2019 &amp;ndash; Below you find a set of charts demonstrating the paths that you can take and the technologies that you would want to adopt in order to become a frontend, backend or a devops. I made these charts for an old professor of mine who wanted something to share with his college students to give them a perspective; sharing them here to help the community. [Top 43 Programming Languages: When and How to Use Them](https://dev.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 19-01-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-190101/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Style beautiful web pages without writing any CSS. Using W3.CSS](https:// dev.to/imalittletester/ style-beautiful-web-pages-without-writing-any-css-using-w3css-45ee) &amp;ndash; a post on how to create beautiful HTML pages which are styled without writing&amp;hellip; [A history of Git](https://medium.com/@willhayjr/ the-architecture-and-history-of-git-a-distributed-version-control-system-62b17dd37742) &amp;ndash; In this comprehensive article, Will Hay Jr. dives into Git’s history, outlining the version control system’s ascent into mass popularity. Along the way, Hay covers Git’s architecture and details some of its shortcomings. [(Less than) 12 Days of Prolog - A guide + brief review of the Prolog programming language] (https://dev.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-12-05</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181205/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181205/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Useful websites for programmers](https://dev.to/sahilrajput/ useful-websites-for-programmers-36k) &amp;ndash; List of some useful websites for programmers and developers. [How to make Python code concurrent with 3 lines](https://dev.to/rhymes/ how-to-make-python-code-concurrent-with-3-lines-of-code-2fpe) &amp;ndash; a great trick. [Shrink your Go binaries with this one weird trick](https://blog.filippo.io/ shrink-your-go-binaries-with-this-one-weird-trick/) &amp;ndash; you can easily reduce a Go binary size by more than 6 times with some flags and common tools. [Results are in for Rust&amp;rsquo;s 2018 survey](https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/11/ 27/Rust-survey-2018.html) &amp;ndash; The Rust survey team has shared the results of its 2018 survey on the state of the language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-11-03</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181103/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181103/</guid>
      <description>Dev [30+ Top MongoDB Interview Questions and Answers](https://dev.to/aershov24/ 30-top-mongodb-interview-questions-and-answers-3d1p) &amp;ndash; The NoSQL database movement came about to address the shortcomings of relational databases and the demands of modern software development. MongoDB is the leading NoSQL database, with significant adoption among the Fortune 500 and Global 500. Interview Questions and Answers (2018 Update). Why you should use pyenv + Pipenv for your Python projects by Daniel van Flymen &amp;ndash; The missing guide for setting up a great local development workflow for your Python projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-10-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181021/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Lifecycle of a Python Code - CPython&amp;rsquo;s Execution Model](https://dev.to/ btaskaya/lifecycle-of-a-python-code&amp;mdash;cpythons-execution-model-85i) &amp;ndash; learning the internals from parsing &amp;amp; tokenization to execution. [Why I use Node.js for basically everything I do](https://medium.com/@kieranmaher13/ why-i-use-nodejs-for-basically-everything-i-do-e0a627787ecc) &amp;ndash; Kieran Maher says Node.js is far too powerful to be limited to just running your website. 50+ data structure and algorithms interview questions for programmers &amp;ndash; Looking for a new job? Take a look at some frequently asked interview questions for programmers of varying levels of experience—from recent grads new to the job market to programmers with several years experience under their belts—to help you practice your pitch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-10-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-181013/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Achieving immutability in Python](https://opensource.com/article/18/10/ functional-programming-python-immutable-data-structures) &amp;ndash; Mutation is hard to reason about. Immutability can help you better understand your code. In part one of a two-part series on functional programming in Python, Moshe Zadka explains why this is the case and shows how to achieve immutability without sacrificing performance. [Hackers (heart) Python](https://www.imperva.com/blog/2018/09/ the-worlds-most-popular-coding-language-happens-to-be-most-hackers-weapon-of-choice) &amp;ndash; Python is on track to become the world&amp;rsquo;s most prevalent coding language. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s just as popular with bad actors as it is with the general population.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-09-29</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180929/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180929/</guid>
      <description>Dev A crash course on Serverless with AWS - Image resize on-the-fly with Lambda and S3 &amp;ndash; Handling large images has always been a pain&amp;hellip;&#xA;PyQt5 tutorial &amp;ndash; Learn how you can create a Python GUI in 2018.&#xA;How Dropbox rolled out one of the largest Python 3 migrations ever &amp;ndash; Dropbox is one of the most popular applications in the world, and much of it is written in Python. Three years ago, the company began moving to Python 3 and has recently finished the migration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-09-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180923/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180923/</guid>
      <description>Dev 50 Python Project &amp;ndash; 50 Popular Python open-source projects on GitHub in 2018. Ops [3 open source log aggregation tools](https://opensource.com/article/18/9/ open-source-log-aggregation-tools) &amp;ndash; Log aggregation is a valuable tool that can help with troubleshooting and other use cases involving event data. Dan Barker takes you through some key considerations and three top tools for log aggregation to help you get started. [Drone: The first open source container-native CI/CD software](https:// thenewstack.io/drone-io-a-containerized-ci-cd-system-for-cloud-native-development) &amp;ndash; Drone is a containerized CI/CD system for cloud-native development, used at companies like eBay and the New York Times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-09-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180909/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180909/</guid>
      <description>Dev A curated Python reading list &amp;ndash; There&amp;rsquo;s nothing like losing yourself in a good book about your favorite programming language. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or a pro, Jen Wike Huger has compiled a list of 18 must-reads.&#xA;How, when, and why to use WebAssembly &amp;ndash; JavaScript is not ideal for every task. That&amp;rsquo;s where WebAssembly comes in.&#xA;Here are tricks and features for Python Pandas that you may not know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-08-31</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180831/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180831/</guid>
      <description>Dev Coder IDE - The Next-gen IDE on the cloud &amp;ndash; a quick review. [The Journey to AWS Certification.](https://dev.to/helenanders26/ the-journey-to-aws-certification-1bnn) [New Playground and Cheatsheet for Learning Python](https://dev.to/trekhleb/ new-playground-and-cheatsheet-for-learning-python-1k8p) &amp;ndash; Collection of Python scripts that are split by topics with comments. 20 [Python Programming Interview Questions](http://www.techbeamers.com/ python-programming-interview-questions-with-answers/) Programmers Should Know. Ops [Linux container deep dive.](http://pierrchen.blogspot.com/2018/08/ understand-container-index.html) Misc Oni &amp;ndash; is a new kind of editor, focused on maximizing productivity - combining modal editing with features you expect in modern editors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-08-24</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180824/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180824/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Be a Better Programmer with these 45 Mathematics Courses](https://hackernoon.com/ be-a-better-programmer-with-these-40-mathematics-courses-d8ca48a2f8a2) &amp;ndash; The Ultimate Course and Book list to be an expert in Mathematics and Programming. [Creating a Chrome extension in 2018: The good, the bad and the meh](https:// hackernoon.com/creating-a-chrome-extension-in-2018-the-good-the-bad-and-the-meh-8efcf6d28322) &amp;ndash; It turns out Chrome extension development is almost like real web development, but with a weird dash of quasi embedded development mixed in. [Shipping PWAs as Chrome Extensions](https://dev.to/samthor/ shipping-pwas-as-chrome-extensions-3l5c) &amp;ndash;incredibly simple (basically all that&amp;rsquo;s left is building a small embedder).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-08-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180813/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180813/</guid>
      <description>Dev Will Python dethrone Java this year? Programming language rankings say yes &amp;ndash; It depends on who you ask, of course, but Java has been on the decline for a while now. [Decorators in Python: What you need to know](https://dev.to/timber/ decorators-in-python-what-you-need-to-know-2iaf) &amp;ndash; a thorough guide on how to write your own decorators, and why. Julia is a high-level dynamic programming language designed to address the needs of high-performance numerical analysis and computational science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-08-08</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180808/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180808/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Rise of Kotlin: The Programming Language for the Next Generation](https:// hackernoon.com/rise-of-kotlin-the-programming-language-for-the-next-generation-27beeb529204) eaturing zan. That exact idea of a highly interoperable and better Java was why this started to attract so many Android developers (including me, having done Android since the early days). [7 features proposed so far in Python 3.8](https://hackernoon.com/ 7-features-proposed-so-far-in-python-3-8-acb0d97c83c8) by Anthony Shaw. Python 3.7 benefitted from both new functionality and optimizations. From what we know so far about 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-07-28</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180728/</guid>
      <description>Dev [RESTful API Design](https://hackernoon.com/ restful-api-design-step-by-step-guide-2f2c9f9fcdbf) &amp;ndash; Step By Step Guide by Tanmay Deshpande. [The Essential Skill of a Developer](https://hackernoon.com/ the-essential-skill-of-a-developer-8f6463b20833 ) &amp;ndash; by Silvestar Bistrović. Ops [What is Docker and How to Use it With Python (Tutorial)](https://dev.to/ django_stars/what-is-docker-and-how-to-use-it-with-python-tutorial-87a) &amp;ndash; an introductory tutorial on Docker containers. 8 books for sysadmins &amp;ndash; recommendations and reviews from opensource.com writer community of their favorite books for admins. [A sysadmin&amp;rsquo;s guide to Ansible: How to simplify tasks](https://opensource.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-07-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180721/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180721/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algorithm in python](https://dev.to/mariamxl/ dijkstras-algorithm-in-python-algorithms-for-beginners-dkc) &amp;ndash; algorithms for beginners: how to find the shortest path between two nodes on a graph. [Get started with GoLang maps: A tutorial](https://www.theserverside.com/blog/ Coffee-Talk-Java-News-Stories-and-Opinions/Get-started-with-GoLang-maps-A-tutorial) &amp;ndash; An important part of programming with GoLang is working with maps. In this tutorial, Walker Rowe (TheServerSide) demonstrates the value of maps and shows how you can integrate them into your programs. Web architecture 101: read this great overview of the basic architecture concepts every web developer should know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-07-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180713/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180713/</guid>
      <description>Dev [WebAssembly + Go = the future of web development](https://brianketelsen.com/ web-assembly-and-go-a-look-to-the-future/) &amp;ndash; GopherAcademy cofounder Brian Ketelsen has resisted learning JavaScript and frontend development. He has been watching WebAssembly with great anticipation, and now that it supports Go, he has concluded that Wasm is the future of web development. WebAssembly (abbreviated Wasm) is a safe, portable, low-level code format designed for efficient execution and compact representation. Its main goal is to enable high performance applications on the Web, but it does not make any Web-specific assumptions or provide Web-specific features, so it can be employed in other environments as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-06-24</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180624/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180624/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Go code refactoring: the 23x performance hunt](https://medium.com/ @val_deleplace/go-code-refactoring-the-23x-performance-hunt-156746b522f7) &amp;ndash; Inspired by an article he had read recently, Good Code vs Bad Code in Golang, Val Deleplace looks at turning &amp;ldquo;bad code&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;good code,&amp;rdquo; which is more idiomatic and legible, making use of the specifics of the Go language. [How to make beautiful, simple CLI apps with Node:](https://dev.to/hugo__df/ how-to-make-beautiful-simple-cli-apps-with-node-c1b) &amp;ndash; a quick walkthrough from dealing with sequential actions to publishing on npm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-06-22</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180622/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180622/</guid>
      <description>Dev [New open source CLI framework from Salesforce](https://engineering.salesforce.com/ open-sourcing-oclif-the-cli-framework-that-powers-our-clis-21fbda99d33a) &amp;ndash; Salesforce engineers are open sourcing some exciting new things you may be interested in. Recently, we open sourced Oclif, a CLI framework that you can use to quickly build your own CLI. Debugging with Git &amp;ndash; let&amp;rsquo;s do some debugging! Here&amp;rsquo;s how to [verify code and encrypt data with Python-GnuPG and Python 3]( https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/ how-to-verify-code-and-encrypt-data-with-python-gnupg-and-python-3). Check out Google’s Bash style guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-06-10</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180610/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180610/</guid>
      <description>Dev [You don&amp;rsquo;t know Bash](https://opensource.com/article/18/5/ you-dont-know-bash-intro-bash-arrays) &amp;ndash; Although software engineers regularly use the command line for many aspects of development, arrays are likely one of the more obscure features of the command line (although not as obscure as the regex operator =~). But obscurity and questionable syntax aside, Bash arrays can be very powerful. Vim Is The Perfect IDE &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped back and forth between many code editors, IDEs and tools; but it seems that somehow I always end up coming right back to VIM, and not only for programming – guess which markdown editor I&amp;rsquo;m using to write this post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-06-02</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180602/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180602/</guid>
      <description>Dev [How To Build Your First Chrome Extension](https://dev.to/himashi99/ how-to-build-your-first-chrome-extension-19lb) &amp;ndash; Changing the Web, One Puppy Image at a Time. Ops [Intro to DevOps: DevOps on a Smaller Scale](https://thenewstack.io/ intro-to-devops-devops-on-a-smaller-scale/) &amp;ndash; DevOps is a really cool intersection in tech where processes, tools, and philosophy all collide. But the things that make it interesting are also the things that make it hard to understand and adopt. As a newcomer to DevOps, Katy Farmer wanted to make it easier for other newcomers to understand the DevOps magic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-05-26</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180526/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180526/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Showdown: MySQL 8 vs PostgreSQL 10.](https://hackernoon.com/ showdown-mysql-8-vs-postgresql-10-3fe23be5c19e) Ops [Getting Started with an Incident Communications Plan.](https:// blog.digitalocean.com/getting-started-with-an-incident-communications-plan/) Gitea &amp;ndash; a community managed fork of Gogs, a painless self-hosted Git service written in Go. In [MySQL 8.0 news](https://mysqlserverteam.com/ mysql-8-0-innodb-now-supports-instant-add-column), InnoDB now supports Instant ADD COLUMN, thanks to the Tencent Games DBA Team. Misc [Аmazing photos of Jupiter](https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/5/21/ 17353110/jupiter-photos-juno-high-res-clouds-great-red-spot) captured by NASA’s Juno spacecraft. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-05-19</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180519/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180519/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Python 3.7: Introducing Data Classes](https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2018 /04/python-37-introducing-data-class/) &amp;ndash; Python 3.7 will be released next month. Take a look at one of its most anticipated features: data classes. Find out what they are and how to use them together with the Star Wars API. Learning Python Like a Pro &amp;ndash; Check out this PyCon 2018 talk about learning and teaching Python with PyCharm Edu, by Liana Bakradze, a member of our Educational Products team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-05-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180513/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180513/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Microservices: A quick and simple definition](www.oreilly.com/ideas/ a-quick-and-simple-definition-of-microservices) &amp;ndash; Curious about microservices? This overview is for you. It covers some of the basics of microservices: what they are, how they work, and what you need to keep in mind before implementing them. [A (crazy?) approach to unit testing in Go](https://medium.com/ @andy.goldstein/a-crazy-approach-to-unit-testing-in-go-3b7160bf9199) &amp;ndash; If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing Andy Goldstein really dislikes about writing unit tests, especially in Go, is that they&amp;rsquo;re typically a pain to write.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-05-05</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180507/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180507/</guid>
      <description>Dev FoundationDB, Apple’s [distributed datastore](https://www.foundationdb.org/ blog/foundationdb-is-open-source/) is also now open source. Ballerina &amp;ndash; a new programming language where microservices, APIs, and streams are first-class constructs. It’s build system is also able to generate Docker and Kubernetes artefacts directly. [How to Use Git Merge (the Correct Way):](https://dev.to/neshaz/ how-to-use-git-merge-the-correctway-25pd) from preparation to dealing with merge conflicts. Ops GraalVM is a universal virtual machine for running applications written in a range of languages, from Java to Python, and C++ to Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-04-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180421/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180421/</guid>
      <description>Dev [The best of Python: favorite articles from 2017 and 2018 (so far)](https:// medium.freecodecamp.org/python-collection-of-my-favorite-articles-8469b8455939) &amp;ndash; IT engineer Gergely Szerovay shares the articles he found most interesting and insightful (inspiring) last year and this year to date. Python enthusiasts and students will appreciate this comprehensive list. [How to use dynamic libraries in C](https://medium.com/@Cu7ious/ how-to-use-dynamic-libraries-in-c-46a0f9b98270) &amp;ndash; Sergii Garkusha looks at why dynamic libraries exist, how they work, and how to create and use them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-04-17</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180417/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180417/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Epic Development Environment using Windows Subsystem for Linux.](https://dev.to/ johnwoodruff91/epic-development-environment-using-windows-subsystem-forlinux-5f0n) &amp;ndash; WSL Setup. Awesome Go: 1400+ Go Links, Libraries and Tools &amp;ndash; A thorough list of Go resources in over 50 categories (think game development, ORMs, NLP, plugins for editors, etc.) that continues to be updated frequently. Learn X in Y minutes &amp;ndash; Take a whirlwind tour of your next favorite language. Community-driven! Ops MacOS Monitoring the Open Source Way &amp;ndash; interesting read about how Dropbox security team monitor the employee laptops to catch malware, using osquery for snapshots, Santa for real-time process events, and OpenBSM/Audit for real-time syscall monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-04-07</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180407/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180407/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Which is the fastest version of Python?](https://hackernoon.com/ which-is-the-fastest-version-of-python-2ae7c61a6b2b) &amp;ndash; “Python 3.7 is the fastest of the “official” Python’s and PyPy is the fastest implementation I tested. I would love to see PyPy3 perform just as well, if not better than PyPy in the future as Python 2 becomes less-used.” [The best programming languages to learn in 2018.](https://medium.freecodecamp.org/ best-programming-languages-to-learn-in-2018-ultimate-guide-bfc93e615b35) &amp;ndash; Alexander Petrov begins his post by stating, &amp;ldquo;This is the definitive guide for anyone wanting to choose the right programming language career path in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-04-01</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180401/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180401/</guid>
      <description>Dev 6 creative ways to solve problems with Linux containers and Docker &amp;ndash; Tools have become such a big focus today that there are many people who haven&amp;rsquo;t spent much time thinking about all the ways containers alone can provide interesting solutions to problems. In this post, Sean Kane takes you on an outside-the-box exploration of how containers can be used to provide novel solutions.&#xA;The modern frontend developer in 2018 &amp;ndash; Kamran Ahmed, currently lead engineer at tajawal, has worn a lot of hats throughout his career and has answered a lot of questions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-03-27</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180327/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180327/</guid>
      <description>Dev gokrazy &amp;ndash; effort to build an all-Go userland for Raspberry Pi, removing memory errors as a source of exploits. [Linux Development Environment of 2018](https://dev.to/brpaz/ my-linux-development-environment-of-2018-ch7) &amp;ndash; command line utilities, graphics and multimedia, DevOps tools, development tools, system utilities, and more. All the tools. [Choosing a Programming Language](https://dev.to/drminnaar/ choosing-a-programming-language-493h) &amp;ndash; the six programming languages you should know, and why. [Learn to code with live streams from the best developers!](https://dev.to/ iriskatastic/learn-to-code-with-live-streams-from-the-best-developers-5fk4) &amp;ndash; a master list of developers who live stream -from PHP to game development, from Java to Webpack, from React.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-03-13</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180313/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180313/</guid>
      <description>Dev [Technical Interview Performance by Editor/OS/Language:](https://dev.to/ triplebyte/technical-interview-performance-by-editoroslanguage&amp;ndash;35kf) data shows there is a correlation between what editor an engineer uses, their language and OS, and their ability to pass programming interviews. How to Design Programs (2nd Edition) &amp;ndash; The purpose of this book is to introduce readers without prior experience to the systematic design of programs. In tandem, it presents a symbolic view of computation, a method that explains how the application of a program to data works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-03-08</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180308/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180308/</guid>
      <description>International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day To celebrate International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day, which happened this week, the Container Camp crew published a list of 36 of the most exciting engineers, community leaders, managers and contributors in the container ecosystem—[newly updated for 2018.](https://medium.com/containercamp/ 35-people-in-container-tech-you-should-be-following-5300bd4766a0) Dev Yun Zhi Lin shares an updated runtime performance benchmark of [all five programming languages](https://read.acloud.guru/ comparing-aws-lambda-performance-of-node-js-python-java-c-and-go-29c1163c2581) supported by AWS Lambda. Ops In this post, Mark McDonnell explores terminology, key monitoring discussion points, and relevant best practices [when instrumenting application performance monitoring](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-03-03</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180303/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180303/</guid>
      <description>Dev How to Debug Any Problem: Step 1: Determine what is working Step 2: Determine precisely what is not working Step 3: Simplify the problem Step 4: Generate hypotheses Step 5: Test hypotheses using divide and conquer Step 6: Think of other versions of this class of bug Step 7: Generate anti-regression tests Step 8: Fix the bug(s) Step 9: Check that the tests now work Step 10: Check the original simple case Step 11: Check the original issue Step 12: Document the fix Step 13: Note any other possible bug classes Step 14: Release Google&amp;rsquo;s programming language Dart has been released with a new vision: as a language uniquely optimized for client-side development for web and mobile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-02-16</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180216/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180216/</guid>
      <description>Dev Happy Friday, happy weekend! Today the Go team is happy to announce the release of Go 1.10. See the Go 1.10 release notes for all the details. Top 50 Developer Tools of 2017. The 100% foolproof way to write secure and bug free code: No code. Linux-ize your Windows machine by setting up these tools for Windows 10. Ops Optimizing web servers for high throughput and low latency. Kernel Recipes 2017 - Performance Analysis with BPF - Brendan Gregg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-02-06</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180206/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180206/</guid>
      <description>Misc What kind of programmer are you? </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-02-03</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180203/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180203/</guid>
      <description>Dev Log To The Rescue Ops Kubernetes for dev infrastructure How to get started on AWS (From a dead standstill) What Tools Do Site Reliability Engineers Use? Misc On-the-rise technology trends to track and learn When developers and tech leaders are figuring out what to do next, how to advance their careers, or offer more value to their companies, they need to know what&amp;rsquo;s hot and what&amp;rsquo;s not living up to the hype.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-02-02</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180127/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180127/</guid>
      <description>Dev Zstd &amp;ndash; a real-time compression algorithm, providing high compression ratios. It offers a very wide range of compression / speed trade-off, while being backed by a very fast decoder. It also offers a special mode for small data, called dictionary compression, and can create dictionaries from any sample set. Zstandard library is provided as open source software using a BSD license. Ben Frederickson became obsessed with the amount of developer activity on sites like GitHub, so he plowed through GitHub Archive and GHTorrent data to plot programming language popularity over a seven year period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-01-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180123/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180123/</guid>
      <description>Dev How to build your own Android ROMs How to turn your side project into an open source project How to speed up Python application startup time Ops 10 open-source Kubernetes tools for highly effective SRE and Ops Teams. If you&amp;rsquo;re running workloads in Kubernetes, your SRE and Ops teams need the right kind of tooling to ensure the high-reliability of the Kubernetes cluster and workloads running in it. Abhishek Tiwari has a list of 10 open-source Kubernetes tools that your SRE and Ops teams will want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-01-18</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180118/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180118/</guid>
      <description>Dev Examining Python&amp;rsquo;s often-overlooked features How to generate GitHub Pages with Hexo, Hugo and Middleman static site generators. Ops hook.io provides an easy way to create, host, and share microservices. The most basic use case for hook.io is quick and free webhook hosting. now – Realtime global deployments. Terraform gotchas and how to work around them Google Services Automation Misc 10 things to increase your productivity in bash System Bus Radio This program transmits radio on computers / phones without radio transmitting hardware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-01-12</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180112/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180112/</guid>
      <description>Dev Meltdown and Spectre. Bugs in modern computers leak passwords and sensitive data: Meltdown Spectre WHY RASPBERRY PI ISN’T VULNERABLE TO SPECTRE OR MELTDOWN Meltdown Proof-of-Concept Interactive Workflows for C++ with Jupyter. How developers will work in 2018 Roadmap to becoming a web developer in 2018 How to integrate Go templates with your application How a RESTful API server reacts to requests Learn how to properly design RESTful APIs communication with clients, accounting for request structure, authentication, and caching.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 18-01-05</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180105/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-180105/</guid>
      <description>Dev Gitmask &amp;ndash; anonymously submit pull requests on GitHub. A Look at Ten New Database Systems Released in 2017 Nerd fonts Matching terminal and vim colors automatically! Ops sed &amp;ndash; An Introduction and Tutorila by Bruce Barnett. Gathering Metrics from Your Infrastructure and Applications. Linux System Administrator/DevOps Interview Questions Misc A Brief Totally Accurate History Of Programming Languages XPS 13 Developer Edition — the 7th gen is here! piu-piu-SH &amp;ndash; Old School horizontal scroller &amp;lsquo;Shoot Them All&amp;rsquo; game in bash.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-12-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171221/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171221/</guid>
      <description>Dev Must have extensions for VS Code (according to me) Top 5 Programming Fonts Ops SSH cheatsheet Misc Google Maps&amp;rsquo; Moat &amp;ndash; detailed (omg so detailed) breakdown of how Google&amp;rsquo;s lead in map data is compounding as they extract more and more value from the data. Cypress &amp;ndash; Fast, easy and reliable testing for anything that runs in a browser. Quantum Game &amp;ndash; open source game play with photons, superposition, and entanglement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-12-12</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171212/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171212/</guid>
      <description>Editors Reddit: Which editor do you use when writing Go DB Comparing MongoDB &amp;amp; MySQL: compares the schema, querying language, relationships, performance/speed, and security of two dominant databases. Dev JavaScript is almost pythonic: a side by side comparison of JavaScript and Python &amp;ndash; multi-line strings, expression interpolations, arrow functions, and more. Regex was taking 5 days to run. So I built a tool that did it in 15 minutes: a story of building for necessity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-12-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171207/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171207/</guid>
      <description>General Examining open source leadership A year into an open source leadership position at the UK GDS, Anna Shipman shares the successes and winning strategy that has enabled community growth and made open source in government self-sustaining.&#xA;Editors Barliman &amp;ndash; Barliman is a prototype &amp;ldquo;smart editor&amp;rdquo; that performs real-time program synthesis to try to make the programmer&amp;rsquo;s life a little easier. Barliman has several unusual features: given a set of tests for some function foo, Barliman tries to &amp;ldquo;guess&amp;rdquo; how to fill in a partially specified definition of foo to make all of the tests pass; given a set of tests for some function foo, Barliman tries to prove that a partially specified definition of foo is inconsistent with one or more of the tests; given a fully or mostly specified definition of some function foo, Barliman will attempt to prove that a partially specified test is consistent with, or inconsistent with, the definition of foo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-12-02</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171202/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171202/</guid>
      <description>Dev Object Models &amp;ndash; a (very) brief run through the inner workings of objects in four very dynamic languages. Readable and informative.&#xA;The controller pattern is awful (and other OO heresy)&#xA;Italic fonts in iTerm2, tmux, and vim&#xA;Programming Fonts&#xA;Ops How to manage Linux containers with Ansible Container&#xA;Adopting Kubernetes step by step.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-30</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171130/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171130/</guid>
      <description>Security WTF Apple?&#xA;Source&#xA;A serious bug in macOS High Sierra lets anyone log into an admin account using the username &amp;ldquo;root&amp;rdquo; with no password. This works when attempting to access an administrator&amp;rsquo;s account on an unlocked Mac, and it also provides access at the login screen of a locked Mac.&#xA;To replicate, follow these steps from any kind of Mac account, admin or guest:&#xA;Open System Preferences.&#xA;Choose Users &amp;amp; Groups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-28</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171128/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171128/</guid>
      <description>Dev The 2017 Top Programming Languages. Ops What is SRE (Site Reliability Engineering)? How To Create a Point-To-Point VPN with WireGuard on Ubuntu 16.04 Misc Wow! Run the First Edition of Unix (1972) with Docker.&#xA;The Computer History Simulation Project. Source on Github.&#xA;Check cryptocurrencies&amp;rsquo; prices changes on your console.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171121/</guid>
      <description>Dev Billions of Emails Synced with Python&#xA;Misc Should you create content in English or in your native language?: a community discussion about whether or not you should create content in English or your native language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-18</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171118/</guid>
      <description>Dev Speed up your Python using Rust. Code together in real time with Teletype for Atom. Nathaniel Schutta on succeeding as a software architect. Datasette (Simon Willison) &amp;ndash; instantly create and publish an API for your SQLite databases. Ops The Ultimate Guide to Secondary DNS Continuous infrastructure: The other CI. How to Monitor the SRE Golden Signals. Binder: an awesome tool for hosting Jupyter notebooks Misc Entering the Quantum Era—How Firefox got fast again and where it’s going to get faster – Mozilla Hacks – the Web developer blog” </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-14</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171114/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171114/</guid>
      <description>Dev Ten interesting features from various modern languages.&#xA;25 Pitfalls When Learning to Program.&#xA;Common security weaknesses every programmer should know.&#xA;Top 7 algorithms and data structures every programmer should know about.&#xA;A month of clean code: a collection of clean code examples, with before &amp;amp; after photos!&#xA;DevOps 5 best practices for container orchestration in IT production.&#xA;Job Do I Want To Work In This Company, or What Questions To Ask On An Interview: questions interviewees can ask to understand the type of company they&amp;rsquo;re interviewing for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-09</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171109/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171109/</guid>
      <description>Dev SQLite Rocks.&#xA;Neugram is a new scripting language, based heavily on Go, but with some useful tricks to cut down on some of the syntax. It also provides a REPL and shebang support.&#xA;Neugram, briefly.&#xA;Misc Resumé++.&#xA;The surprising longevity of mainframes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-05</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171105/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171105/</guid>
      <description>Dev What are the Most Disliked Programming Languages?&#xA;Why Go is skyrocketing in popularity?&#xA;Connecting to Google Sheets with Python.&#xA;KotlinConf Keynote Recap.&#xA;DevOps How To Set Up Your Linode For Maximum Awesomeness.&#xA;Why is Kubernetes so popular?&#xA;AWX is the open source project behind Red Hat Ansible Tower, offering developers access to the latest features, and the opportunity to directly collaborate with the Ansible Tower engineering team. 5 thing you can do with AWX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-11-03</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171103/</guid>
      <description>Dev 5 things to do whenever you start a new project.&#xA;Code review checklist.&#xA;The role, skills, and duties of a software architect.&#xA;CLI Using better CLIs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-10-27</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171027/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171027/</guid>
      <description>Misc Awesome blockchains.&#xA;Huginn is a system for building agents that perform automated tasks for you online.&#xA;DevDocs opensource Dash competitor. Web version.&#xA;Mesosphere CEO Florian Leibert interview about the history of containers and where distributed systems are heading in the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-10-26</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171026/</guid>
      <description>Dev 19 Types of Developers Explained&#xA;Developer roadmap</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-10-21</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171021/</guid>
      <description>Dev What it’s like to be a developer at …&#xA;Home is where the work is&#xA;Lang GetStream.io: Why We Switched from Python to Go&#xA;5 Reasons Why We switched from Python To Go&#xA;Why should you learn Go?&#xA;Go vs CPython: Visual comparison of concurrency and parallelism options&#xA;Misc TiddlyWiki — a non-linear personal web notebook</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-10-17</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171017/</guid>
      <description>Security Krack Attack &amp;ndash; force WPA2 to reuse a key, making your secure network roll over and expose its soft underbelly. The bug is in the protocol, not any particular implementation. As a friend pointed out, many wireless ISPs use WPA2-PSK to auth their subscriber terminals. The blood will flow from far more than your home WiFi network&#xA;How Apple Killed iOS Jailbreaking &amp;ndash; First, they force their opponent to find four vulnerabilities; fixing any one of which breaks the jailbreak and forces the attacker to find a new flaw that serves the same purpose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-10-14</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-171014/</guid>
      <description>AI Generating Faces with Deconvolution Networks&#xA;Microsoft and Amazon join forces on an Gluon AI library, hoping to unseat (or at least rival) Google&amp;rsquo;s tools.&#xA;Editors Interview: A leading Django development consultancy gains speed and efficiency with PyCharm</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-09-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170923/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170923/</guid>
      <description>Misc Technical Interview Performance by Editor/OS/Language&#xA;Humor DocWriter: the typewriter that sends its keystrokes in real time to a Google Doc</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-09-15</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170915/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170915/</guid>
      <description>Editors This week, the team at GitHub launched Atom-IDE, bringing IDE-like functionality to the open source editor Atom.&#xA;Sublime Text 3.0 is released.&#xA;О-о-очень долгожданный релиз Sublime Text 3.0.&#xA;Programming Pyenv is a simple tool that lets you change between different Python versions either globally or on a per-project basis.&#xA;Build a working game of Tetris in Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life.&#xA;What every software engineer should know about search.&#xA;Python Packaging Python projects with pbr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-09-02</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170902/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170902/</guid>
      <description>The evolution of DevOps Understanding the impact and expanding influence of DevOps culture, and how to apply DevOps principles to make your digital operations more performant and productive.&#xA;CLI productivuty 10 Plain Text Files You Should Have on Your Desktop for Higher Productivity.&#xA;Cleaning email unroll.me cleans up your inbox.&#xA;Kill the Newsletter! converts email newsletters into Atom feeds.&#xA;grammarly.com&#xA;Vim vim keyboard challenge&#xA;Главные сериалы сентября Лайфхакер собрал подборку из самых ожидаемых премьер и уже полюбившихся сериалов, которые выйдут в этом месяце.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-08-26</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170826/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170826/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.9 fresh from the vine Improvements in runtime and tooling underpin the latest release of Go. Of particular note is the introduction of type aliases, a feature created to support gradual code repair, and the new math/bits package.&#xA;Open to interpretation Have you ever wanted to create your own programming language from scratch? In &amp;ldquo;three easy steps&amp;rdquo; Francis Stokes shows you what goes into writing your very own interpreter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buku workflow for Alfred 3</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/buku/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 11:49:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/buku/</guid>
      <description>This is Alfred workflow for CLI bookmark manager buku.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-08-12</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170812/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170812/</guid>
      <description>A Python module for learning major algorithms Folks just starting out with Python can find all the major sort and search algorithms in one Python module with Pygorithm. No need to surf around for example code; just install the module and start exploring.&#xA;Everyone is not Ops&#xA;The SRE model&#xA;Justifying the cost of application monitoring tools</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-08-06</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170804/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170804/</guid>
      <description>~/.vim/colors&#xA;SafariStand for Safari 10&#xA;Site Reliability Engineering&#xA;[How To Use Certbot Standalone Mode to Retrieve Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt SSL Certificates] (https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-use-certbot-standalone-mode-to-retrieve-let-s-encrypt-ssl-certificates)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-07-29</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170729/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170729/</guid>
      <description>Everyone Can Code: Apple&amp;rsquo;s Attempt to Make Coding Commonplace&#xA;Python Entry Points Explained</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links 17-07-23</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170723/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/links-170723/</guid>
      <description>Programming The 2017 Top Programming Languages. Python jumps to No. 1, and Swift enters the Top Ten.&#xA;Parsing In Python: Tools And Libraries.&#xA;Text editors Editor config&#xA;Workspace setup Brian Hendrix’s Mac setup&#xA;Books Mastering Bitcoin 2nd Edition - Programming the Open Blockchain, Russian translation, pdf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Translit Alfred 3 workflow</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/translit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 14:32:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/translit/</guid>
      <description>This is Alfred &amp;ldquo;translit&amp;rdquo; workflow. It fix mistakes when entering cyrillic text in wrong input locale (english) and automatically switches keyboard layout. In short it does the same as the Punto Swither does.&#xA;To work correctly you need input source switcher and Python3.&#xA;To install workflow in Alfred, download latest release an import it by clicking in Finder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shimo workflow for Alfred 3</title>
      <link>https://gobunov.com/posts/shimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:44:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gobunov.com/posts/shimo/</guid>
      <description>This is Alfred workflow for Shimo VPN sofware. It control configured VPN connections.&#xA;Workflow keyword is shimo. That run Shimo.app if not already runnig and show all your VPN accounts. Case insensitive autocompletion work on the argument if one is provided.&#xA;Selecting account toggles connection status depending on the current status.&#xA;To install workflow in Alfred, download latest release an import it by clicking in Finder.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
